hey uncle and welcome to crash course AI
one way to make an artificial brain is
by creating a neural network which can
have millions of neurons and billions or
trillions of connections between them
nowadays some neural networks are fast
and big enough to do some tasks even
better than humans can
like for example playing chess or
predicting the weather but as we've
talked about in crash course AI no
networks don't just work on their own
they need to learn to solve problems for
making mistakes sounds kind of like us
right
[Music]
neuro-networks handle mistakes by using
an algorithm called back propagation to
make sure all the neurons that
contributed to an error get their math
adjusted and we'll unpack this a bit
later and neural networks have two main
parts the architecture and the weights
the architecture includes neurons and
their connections and the weights are
numbers that fine-tune how the neurons
compute an output so if a neural network
makes a mistake this often means the
weights aren't adjusted correctly and we
need to update them so they make better
predictions next time the task of
finding the best ways for a neural
network architecture is called
optimization and the best way to
understand some basic principles of
optimization is with an example with the
help of my pal John Green but say that I
manage a swimming pool and I want to
predict how many people will come next
week so that I can schedule enough
lifeguards a simple way to do this is by
graphing some data points like the
number of swimmers and the temperature
in Fahrenheit for every day over the
past few weeks then we can look for a
pattern in that graph to make
predictions the way computers do this is
with an optimization strategy called
linear regression we start by drawing a
random straight line on the graph which
kind of fits the data points to optimize
though we need to know how incorrect
this guess is so we calculate the
distance between the line and each of
the data points add it all up and that
gives us the error
we're quantifying how big a mistake
we've made the goal of linear regression
is to adjust the line to make the errors
as small as possible we want the line to
fit the training data as much as it can
the result is called the line of best
fit we can use this straight line to
predict how many swimmers will show up
for any temperature but parts of it defy
logic
for example super cold days have a
negative number
while dangerously hot days have way more
people than the pool can handle to get
more accurate results we might want to
consider more than two features like for
example adding the humidity would turn
our 2d graph into 3d and our line of
best fit would be more like a plane
best fit but if we added a fourth
feature like whether it's raining or not
suddenly we can't visualize this anymore
so as we consider more features we add
more dimensions to the graph the
optimization problem gets trickier and
fitting the training data is tougher
this is where our neural networks come
in handy basically by connecting
together many simple neurons with
weights a neural network can learn to
solve complicated problems where the
line of best fit becomes a weird
multi-dimensional function
let's give John Green bot an untrained
neural network to stick with the same
example the input layer of this neural
network takes features like temperature
humidity rain and so on and the output
layer predicts the number of swimmers
that will come to the pool we're not
gonna worry about designing the
architecture John Green BOTS no network
right now let's just focus on the
weights he'll start as always by setting
the weights to random numbers like the
random line on the graph we drew earlier
only this time it's not just one random
line because he has lots of inputs it's
lots of lines that are combined to make
one big messy function overall there's
no networks function resembles some
weird multi-dimensional shape that we
don't really have a name for to train
this known network we'll start by giving
John Green bought a bunch of
measurements from the past 10 days at
the swimming pool because these are the
days where we also know the output
attendance will start with one day where
else 80 degrees Fahrenheit 65% humidity
and not raining which will represent
with zero the neurons would do their
thing by multiplying those features by
the weights adding the results together
and passing information to the hidden
layers into the output neuron has an
answer what do you think John Green
bought just like before there is a
difference between the neural networks
output and the actual swimming pool
attendance which was recorded as a
hundred people because we have just one
output neuron the difference of 45
people is the error
pretty simple and some neural networks
though the output layer may have a lot
of neurons so the difference between the
predicted answer and the correct answer
is more than just one number in these
cases the error is represented by what's
known as a loss function moving forward
we need to adjust the neural networks
weight so that the next time we give
John Green bought similar inputs his
math and final output will be more
accurate
basically we need John Green bot to
learn from his mistakes a lot like when
we push the button a supervises learning
when he had the perception program but
this is a bit trickier because of how
complicated neural networks are to help
no networks learn scientists and
mathematicians came up with an algorithm
called back propagation of the error or
just back propagation for sure
the basic goal is to look at the loss
function and then assign blame to
neurons back in the previous layers of
the network some neurons calculations
may be more to blame for the air than
others so the weights will be adjusted
more this information is fed backwards
which is where the idea of back
propagation comes from so for example
the error from our output neuron will go
back a layer and adjust the weights that
get applied to our hidden layer neuron
outputs and the error from our hidden
layer neurons will go back a layer to
adjust the weights that get applied to
our features remember our goal is to
find the best combination of weights to
get the lowest error to explain logic
behind optimization with the metaphor
let's send John and green ba on a
metaphorical journey through the
thought-bubble
let's imagine that weights in our neural
network are like latitude and longitude
coordinates on the map and the error of
our neural network is the altitude lower
is better John Green bought the Explorer
is on a quest to find the lowest point
in the deepest Valley the latitude and
longitude of the lowest point where the
error is the smallest are the weights of
the neural networks global optimal
solution but John Green bot has no idea
where this valley actually is by
randomly setting the initial weights of
our known Network
we're basically dumping him in the
middle of the jungle all he knows is his
current latitude longitude and altitude
maybe we got lucky and he's on the side
of the deepest Valley but he could also
be at the top of the highest mountain
far away the only way to know is to
explore because the jungle is so dense
it's hard to see very far the best John
Green bot can do is look around and make
a guess he notices he can descend down a
little by moving northeast so he takes a
step down and updates his latitude and
longitude from this new position he
looks around and picks another step that
increases his altitude a little more and
then another and another with every
brave step he updates his coordinates
and decreases his altitude eventually
John Green bot looks around and finds
that he can't go down any more he
celebrates because it seems like he
found the lowest point in the deepest
Valley or so he thinks if we look at the
whole map we can see that John Green bot
only filmed the bottom of a small Gorge
when he ran out of down it's way better
than where he started but it's
definitely not the lowest point of the
deepest Valley so he just found a local
optimal solution where the weights make
the error relatively small but not the
smallest it could be sorry buddy thanks
thought-bubble
back propagation and learning always
involves lots of little steps and
optimization is tricky with any neural
network if we go back to our example of
optimization as exploring a map we're
never quite sure if we're headed in the
right direction or if we've reached the
lowest Valley with the smallest error
again that's the global optimal solution
but tricks have been discovered to help
us better navigate for example when we
drop and explore somewhere on the map
they could be really far from the lowest
Valley with a giant mountain range in
the way so it might be a good idea to
try different random starting points to
make sure the no network isn't getting
stuck at a local optimal solution or
instead of restarting over and over
again we could have a team of explorers
that start from different locations and
explore the jungle simultaneously this
strategy of exploring different
solutions at the same time on the same
neural network is especially useful when
you have a giant computer with lots of
processors and we can even adjust the
Explorer step size so they can step
right over small Hills as you try and
find into sin into a valley this step
size is called the learning rate and
it's how much the neurons weights get
adjusted every time back propagation
happens we're always looking for more
creative ways to explore solutions try
different combinations of weights and
minimize the loss function as we train
neural networks but even if we use a
bunch of training data and back
propagation to find the global optimal
solution we're still only halfway done
the other half of training is an AI
checking whether the system can answer
new questions it's easy to solve a
problem we've seen before like taking a
test after studying the answer key we
may get an A but we actually didn't
learn much to really test what we
learned we need to solve problems we've
never seen before same goes for neural
networks this whole time John Green bot
has been training his new network with
swimming pool data his new network has
dozens of features like temperature
humidity rain day week and wind speed
but also grass length number of
butterflies around the pool and the
average GPA of the lifeguards more data
can be better for finding patterns in
accuracy as long as the computer can
handle it over time back propagation
will adjust the neurons weights so that
the known networks output matches the
training data remember
that's called fitting to the training
data and with this complicated neural
network we're looking for a multi
dimensional function and sometimes back
propagation is too good at making a
neural network fit to certain data see
there are lots of coincidental
relationships in big datasets like for
example the divorce rate in Maine may be
correlated with us
Largent consumption or skin revenue may
be correlated with the number of people
dying by getting trapped in their
bedsheets neural networks are really
good at finding these kind of
relationships and it can be a big
problem because if we give a neuro
network some new data that doesn't
adhere to these silly correlations then
it will probably make some strange
errors that's the danger known as
overfitting the easiest way to prevent
overfitting is to keep the neural
networks simple if we retrain John Green
BOTS swimming pool program without data
like grass length and number of
butterflies and we observed that our
accuracy doesn't change then ignoring
those features is for the best
so training a neural network isn't just
a bunch of math we need to consider how
to best represent our various problems
as features and AI systems and to think
carefully about what mistakes these
programs might make next time well jump
into our very first lab in the course
when we'll apply all this knowledge and
build a neural network together I'll see
you in the lab crash course AI is
produced in association with PBS Digital
Studios if you wanna help keep crash
course free for everyone forever you can
join our community on patreon and if you
don't learn more about the math behind
k-means clustering check out this video
from crash course statistics
[Music]